<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on ESA QERC</title>
    <link>https://esa-qerc.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on ESA QERC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://esa-qerc.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>QERC-y chat - R package dev</title>
      <link>https://esa-qerc.github.io/post/06_20210621qercychat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esa-qerc.github.io/post/06_20210621qercychat/</guid>
      <description>Monday 19th of July 3:45 - 4:45pm on zoom. Our second community chat is all about R package development! When should your piece of code become a package? Where should that package end up (e.g., CRAN, GitHub)? When should we start writing documentation and unit tests? Do standard practices work with all applications (e.g., big data and models)? For the July QERC-y chat, we are excited to be joined by Dr Emi Tanaka (Monash University) to discuss our experiences, hacks and potential trip hazards with packaging up our code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing... QERC-y chats!</title>
      <link>https://esa-qerc.github.io/post/04_introqercychat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esa-qerc.github.io/post/04_introqercychat/</guid>
      <description>2020 was a tough year.
Our preoccupation with the pandemic, hand sanitation, and hoarding toilet paper meant that QERC was not able to run any events&amp;hellip;but we are back!
We are excited to introduce to you all to QERC-y chats (pronounced quirky chats) - a series of community chats where quantitative ecologists come together and engage in discussions on topics ranging from mathematics and statistics to coding practices.
We invite you to join us and contribute to these discussions and help guide future events!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QERC-y chat - to tidy to too tidy?</title>
      <link>https://esa-qerc.github.io/post/05_20210517qercychat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esa-qerc.github.io/post/05_20210517qercychat/</guid>
      <description>Monday 17th of May 3:45 - 4:45pm on zoom.
The first of our community chats is all about tidyverse! Tidyverse is a bundle of RStudio packages that are intended to be used in harmony. Do pipes, purrr, and ggplots spark joy in your workflow? Does using tidyverse have to be all-or-nothing? In this 45 minute QERC-y chat, we will chat about our experience with tidyverse and discuss where tidiness prevails and when it falls short for R users of varying skill levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AIMOS 2019 Workshop on reproducibility research in R</title>
      <link>https://esa-qerc.github.io/post/02_aimos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esa-qerc.github.io/post/02_aimos/</guid>
      <description>QERC is hosting a workshop at the AIMOS conference (Interdisciplinary Meta-research and Open Science conference) in Melbourne on 7-8 November 2019 in Melbourne. Details about the conference and the workshop can be found on the conference website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESA 2019 Workshop on reproducibility research in R</title>
      <link>https://esa-qerc.github.io/post/03_esa2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esa-qerc.github.io/post/03_esa2019/</guid>
      <description>QERC is hosting a workshop at the ESA 2019 conference on 27 November 2019 in Launceston, Tasmania. Details about the conference and the workshop can be found on the conference website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESA 2018 Quantitative Ecology Showcase</title>
      <link>https://esa-qerc.github.io/post/01_showcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esa-qerc.github.io/post/01_showcase/</guid>
      <description>Whilst QERC was officially established in 2019, the organisers ran a two-day Quantitative Ecology Showcase as part of the 2018 ESA Annual meeting. You can read about it on the conference website</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
